<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="rules_array">

        <item>
            %title Attacks of opportunity !%
            If a creature leaves another creature controlled area (this area is defined by the range
            of the creature weapon.s) or loss its focus on the latter, this one can do an attack of
            opportunity on the former. This
            attack do not use any AP but need to spend flux. The flux cost of the first attack is 50
            and doubles (100, 200, 400, etc) for every new attack of opportunity before the start of the attacker turn.
        </item>

        <item>
            %title Movement !%
            For 1 AP a creature can move up to its movement value. If the creature moves through a
            hazardous terrain, the "length" needed to cross it may increase. The creature may not have
            this penalty inflicted, but in this case, it exposes itself to an acrobatics check in
            order not to fall and end its turn.
        </item>

        <item>
            %title Ranged action !%
            A ranged action is an action with a range above the creature reach or reach of its melee weapon.\n
            If a creature tries to do a ranged action while being in the controlled area of another creature, the latter can do an attack of opportunity on the former.\n
            If an ranged action need a touch check to be successful and the target is in melee with another creature, the ranged action is given a disadvantage not to risk hitting the other creature.
            The disadvantage can be removed but the ranged action can then hit the other creature (the probability of hitting the creature depends on the angle between the protagonist, the target and the creature).
            In this case, the GM first rolls to determine the target and keeps it a secret. Then the action takes place normally but with the target updated.
        </item>

    </string-array>

</resources>